本字幕由「泉水渗透进字幕组」制作
■
翻译：GPT-4        听写：Whisper       校对&后期：yojoU
2011年11月
In November of 2011,
NBC热播情景喜剧《废柴联盟》的演职人员
the cast and crew of NBC's hit sitcom Community
发现他们的预算严重超支  且进度落后
found themselves hopelessly over budget and behind schedule.
创剧人丹哈萌的解决办法 ——
Creator Dan Harmon's solution?
拍一个两集的特别篇
Create a two-part episode,
两集使用完全相同的道具  布景和服装
the second part using all the same props, sets, and costumes as the previous.
他们将面临电视网历史上一项前所未有的挑战
Together they would face one of the biggest challenges ever faced in network television history,
编一部长篇战争纪录片风格的喜剧
writing comedy in the style of a really, really long documentary about war.
他们从一开始就知道他们肩负的风险
They knew at the outset the risks they were taking,
但他们不在乎
but they didn't care.
以下是他们的故事
This is their story.
你好  我是切维·切斯
Hello, I'm Chevy Chase.
这里大部分的工作都有我的功劳
Most of what's going on around here has to do with me.
这种风格很容易模仿
The style is very easy to emulate.
现在我们经常看到纪录片在无休止地模仿这种风格
It's something that we see all the time now, imitated by documentaries endlessly.
这集包含了很多静止的照片和大段旁白
It involves a lot of still photographs and narration and kind of a moving
通过静景之上的镜头运动叙事
camera on still photographs to kind of narrate the story.
叙事方式包括  画外音
The story being told through someone else's voice,
一些真人动作和慢动作镜头
some live action, some slow motion
以及大量静景和访谈
and a lot of stills and talking heads.
开始读剧本时  读到静景
When you start reading, you're like, stills,
会感到一头雾水
I'm not quite sure what's happening.
然后当了解到  要呈现这场类似内战的场景时
And then the idea that they were just going to do this whole sort of civil war,
会感觉很酷  因为要重现之前拍摄的场景
it just felt really cool because you were recreating these scenes that you shot,
但是要用手机来拍
but now it's cell phone footage
再加上
and you know, uh...
被布雷塔拍得很烂的照片
Britta's terrible picture she's taking.
我昨天演了我的第一段自白
I had my first confessional yesterday and
我不知道是该搞笑
I didn't know, is it supposed to be funny?
还是该严肃
Is it supposed to be serious?
他们说  这可是战争  伊薇特
And they were like, this is war, Yvette.
你在战争中会有什么感受
How would you feel in a war?
我说  那可就非同一般了  我会非常严肃的
And I said, well, that changes everything, I'd be very serious.
这集的准备工作有所不同  因为我们的台词不多
It's kind of a different type of preparation because we don't have as many lines,
重点更多在于角色的态度和心理状态
it's more like the attitude and what's going on with the characters
整体氛围也更加严肃
and it's much more serious,
感觉更加地...
it kind of seems like a more...
我们需要营造许多特别的瞬间
We had to create a bunch of moments,
就很随性地进入场景
it's just like coming in and just like
因为所有的拍摄都是手持的  或者使用手机之类的设备
cuz it's supposed to, like all the stuff is handheld and stuff or on phones and stuff like that,
所以很多地方需要营造出一种即兴感
so it's a lot of like making it feel like it's impromptu.
我们用常规电影摄影机进行了整个战斗场面的拍摄
We did the whole battle with regular motion picture cameras,
而且还用了数码相机
or they're all digital cameras now.
我们先把所有对话拍一遍  再用相机重现一遍
So we did all the dialogue we did for that and then we kind of staged the same thing,
用的好像是佳能5D相机
but they were just using a... I think Canon 5D camera
但只抓拍了剧本中描述的几个瞬间
to just capture a couple of moments that are described in the script.
导演快崩溃了
And the director lost his mind
因为要布置这些相当复杂的照片场景
because he had to stage these fairly intricate photographs.
编剧可以很淡定地说  你通常每秒拍30帧
It was easy enough for the writers to say, you usually shoot 30 frames per second, so
现在只要拍一帧  我觉得应该简单30倍  对吧
this is just one frame for, I mean, it should be 30 times easier, right?
至少有70张照片要拍  再加上地图的镜头
There's at least 70 still photographs to take and we've got map footage and
这会很精彩
it's gonna be fantastic.
我讨厌静景
I hate still.
我在静景镜头里很丑
I just look terrible in still shots.
我甚至不喜欢照镜子  除非是刮胡子
I don't even like to look in the mirror except to shave.
如果那些照片是在动景中拍的
If those shots are taken in the midst of motion
并且我没察觉到  那就行
and I don't know about it, that's great.
如果要我凹造型  呃  我讨厌这样
If I have to pose, I, ugh, I hate it.
我想在这一季中让他们的友谊更加立体
I wanted to dimensionalize their friendship this season,
不是破坏他们的友谊  而是
not by tarnishing it, but just
通过展现一个真实版本的友谊
by demonstrating that there was a real version
让它看起来不那么卡通
of what otherwise seemed sort of cartoony.
这对形影不离的死党
These two best friends who seemed completely inseparable
别人一直调侃他们的亲密关系
and that being a joke for so long.
特洛伊和阿布蒂  他们意气相投
Troy and Abed, they never don't like each other,
他们一体同心
they never don't think the same thing.
我想用一种更贴近现实的社交视角来审视这一季
I wanted to look at it this season through a lens of slightly more realistic social dynamics
特别强调了阿布蒂这个角色
with an emphasis on the idea that Abed is a character
与特洛伊在本质上的不同
who is different from Troy in a fundamental way.
这是本剧的一个关键时刻
It's a nice monumental turning point for the show
他们的友谊
where their friendship is
将面临一种只有他们才能经历的独特考验
tested in a way that only Troy and Abed can test their friendship.
你应该把小的放在中间  不然墙撑不住天花板
为啥总是我来当你的雷吉
你想说啥
我想建一个毯子城堡  这事你想都没想过
我连你的副手都算不上  就是个小跟班
我没不让你干什么啊
你要是想建毯子城堡  我没意见
谢谢
只要别和我的枕头堡沾边
刚开始  我对丹哈萌有点表示怀疑
Early on, I was sort of gently pushing back to Dan Harmon saying like,
开玩笑吗  在NBC周四晚八点的黄金档
really for on a Thursday night, eight o'clock on NBC,
在电视上这样玩
like on network television we're gonna do this
这难道不是大家经常批评的
And isn't this what people complain about,
觉得我们的剧太另类  太高冷吗
that we're too weird and that the inaccessible
但他坚持说  正因如此  我们才必须这么做
and he kept saying, that's why we have to do it.
他一直强调  这绝对行得通
He kept saying, no, it'll work.
最棘手的挑战在于第二集的创作
The biggest challenge was in the writing of the second episode
因为需要堆砌词藻
because you have to get very wordy.
我们尝试去模拟一种风格
You're trying to emulate a style
这通常是以戏剧性而非喜剧性的方式呈现
that is usually rolled out, not only dramatically as opposed to communically
而且需要3小时甚至更长时间来展开
but in three hours or more.
我想  我们在制作过程中经常会相视而笑
And I think we're finding, we've had plenty of moments when we were making this and
心里暗自得意地想着  没错  没错  是这样
we thought that we kind of smiled devilishly to each other thinking like, yeah, yeah, yeah,
这个真的会很棒
I think this is going to be great.
我们在第二季搭过一个毯子城堡
We had done a blanket fort episode on season two,
所以我们对此有一定经验
so we kind of knew what was going on but
但枕头堡的搭建就更加复杂了
with the pillow fort, it's a little more complicated
毕竟  考虑到阿布蒂的个性  他会把每个细节做到极致
because, of course being who Abed is would do like this perfect job
确保一切在理论上精准无误
and make sure everything is mathematically correct
并保持美观上的协调
and aesthetically the kind of the same.
我们从本剧片头的折纸游戏这种小点子出发
We've taken the idea of something like the cootie catcher, which is the beginning of the show
进一步深化这个概念
and you know, extrapolated the idea.
当我们读到网格球顶的部分时  都在想  哇
We read the geodesic dome and that was something we thought, oh, gee,
这怎么可能实现呢
how is that going to happen, but
好在我们的搭景协调员约翰·理查森  找来了个
But our construction coordinator, John Richardson, found a...
火人节上别人用过的网格球顶
a geodesic dome that someone had from Burning Man
而且价格非常合理
and it was like really inexpensive,
比我们自己从头开始建造要便宜得多
you know, compared to having to build everything.
我们还特别注意颜色上的差异
We also wanted to color differentiations.
我们寻求具有质感的面料
We tried to shop fabrics that were textural
所以使用了大量的灯芯绒
so that there's a lot of corduroy in the set.
初次采购就像一场寻宝  要找到能体现角色个性的物品
It was like the first shopping trip was to find things that were, that spoke to the characters
我还有相当一部分工作  为角色挑选适合的颜色
and a lot of what I was doing was also finding the colors that I thought they'd look good in.
我们真应该对我们的美术组表示赞赏
We should compliment like the art department here because they are incredible.
他们搭建的枕头和毯子城堡非常出色
And like building the pillows and the blanket forts.
枕头堡令人赞叹  我真希望我家里也有一个
Like the pillow fort is by far like, I wish that was in my house, like it's so,
它不仅复杂精致而且非常酷  你甚至可以在里面爬行
it's so intricate and really cool and like you can crawl through it.
这不是胡说八道  也不是电脑特效
It's not like, it's not bulls, it's not computers.
我不清楚别人怎么想的
I don't know what people think.
我亲眼见证了它的建造过程  很壮观
I saw it being built and I thought this is spectacular.
每次想到我们居然能在毯枕堡里拍摄  我都很震惊
It's always so amazing to me that we're actually able to shoot in the blanket fort, in the pillow fort
因为它们外表看起来很小
cuz it looks so small from the outside and
他们竟能把摄影机  灯光  演员  收音这一切都安置好
the fact that they can get cameras and lights and actors and sound and everything in there
这让我印象深刻
is always so impressive to me.
这种情况每周都会发生  但这次他们拆学校的原因是
And they do this every week on the show, but they once again had to destroy the campus
玩枕头大战
this time in a pillow fight.
搞得满地羽毛
So there's feathers everywhere.
他们建造了这个巨型枕头堡
They created these massive pillow forts that
并按照剧本中要求的那样  看起来构造精巧
we said in the script, need to look like they're architecturally sophisticated
他们真的做到了
and they did.
这太不可思议了
It's insane.
枕头堡是由每块2x4英尺的部分组成的
The pillow fort is constructed like in two by four foot sections.
我们可以根据拍摄需求移开一些侧壁
So we can wild out some of the walls as we need to
也可以拆除一些天花板
and we can take off some of the ceilings
方便我们布置灯光
so they can throw light in and we have accessibility.
我们还设置了一些独立的柱子和角落
And we have like columns, freestanding columns and corners
这样就可以调整这些部分
so we can move those pieces around
让它看起来像枕头堡的不同区域
so it looks like we're in a different part of the pillow fort.
我一直都觉得  我们的美术和道具组做事非常认真细致
I've always said this, our art department and our prop department are so thorough.
他们在有限的预算下做出了令人惊叹的布景和道具
They create amazing sets and props and whatever like on a dime.
剧本可能会突然要求  需要一个完全用枕头装扮的角色
We literally will get pages and it's like oh so we need to have someone dressed in pillows completely
服装道具组的所有人都会立刻行动起来
and the word department and the props and everybody's going to say
他们会各司其职
okay we're going to do this and I'm going to bring this in and
这真是一个由极具创造力的人组成的团队
it's like a great group of people that really are creative
他们能迅速应对各种突发状况
and can do anything at the drop of a dime.
在皮尔斯的想象中  他一定是最出色的战士
I think in Pierce's mind he would be the finest soldier.
你能造出来吗
你得给我提供枕头
希望我们永远也不会用上它
我也这么想
杰夫绝不愿意弄乱他的发型
Hey we'll hurry cause Jeff didn't want his hair to get messed up.
他不可能穿睡衣  但会穿那种有点行动不便的衣服
He's not gonna be wearing pajamas so he might be wearing something that's hindering him a little bit
他只要风度不要温度
but he will sacrifice anything for fashion.
我选伦纳德
I'm gonna go with Leonard.
雪莉很厉害
Shirley's pretty good.
雪莉很勇猛
Shirley's really good.
是的
Yeah.
就像在剧集中看到的那样  她似乎有点战争狂的倾向
I mean she's got, I mean like we've seen in other episodes that she's kind of like a war monger.
是的  她似乎总是在等待这些混乱的时刻  你突然会发现
Yeah she kind of waits for these moments where there's chaos and all of a sudden you're like
好吧  原来她这么能打
oh okay you are good at battle.
雪莉显然非常骁勇善战
Shirley apparently is very good in combat.
我们在两次彩弹大战集就发现了这一点
We found that out in the first paintball episode, the second paintball episode
这已经是在格林戴尔校园发生的第三次大战
and now this is the third epic battle that has taken place on Greendale's campus and
雪莉在必要时能够彻底击溃敌人
Shirley really rises up and destroys human beings when she needs to.
我非常擅长被动进攻
I'm a very passive aggressive fighter.
打中了  好了我挂了
别打了  我挂了
我是最会耍手段的战士
I'm the dirtiest fighter in the game.
我私认为是  院长
I think I'm selfishly going to just say the Dean
因为如果他加入到学习小组的枕头大战中
only cuz if he got into a pillow fight with the study group
他可能会忙着乱摸  其他人就被吓跑了
he'd probably just do a lot of groping, they'd want to leave.
我们小组里的每个成员都很机智
Everybody's pretty crafty in our group.
我觉得不能轻视任何一个人
I don't think you could count anyone out
因为他们通常都有备而来  并暗藏杀机
because they usually have a couple of tricks up their sleeve.
我们是一群没有道德底线  冷酷无情的人
We're a bunch of amoral ruthless people so
这将是一场持续到底的七方角逐
it'd be a seven-way battle to the end.
毯子还是枕头
Blanket or pillow person?
枕头很舒服  很可爱  很柔软
Pillows are comfortable and cuddly and soft
毯子提供温暖
and blankets provide warmth.
毯子
Blanket.
谁会选枕头呢
Who would choose this pillow?
我猜丹尼会选择枕头
I think Danny's gonna choose pillow.
我大概会选枕头
I would probably have to go with pillow.
比起温暖我更喜欢柔软  所以我选择枕头
I think I prefer softness to heat so I'm going pillows.
不对
No.
我选毯子  因为毯子可以卷起来当枕头用
I'd go with blanket I think because blankets can be rolled into pillows.
枕套里还能存放东西
You could store stuff in a pillowcase.
比如在末日时刻  你可以在里面装东西  方便携带
Like if there's the apocalypse you could put stuff in there and you can carry it.
我可以不用枕头
I can do without a pillow you know
我喜欢毯子  它晚上能给我温暖
I like blankets, it keeps me warm at night.
毯子无疑
Blanket. Easily.
我想说  任何东西都能变成枕头
I mean I think, I think you can make anything into a pillow but
但毯子的温度是无可替代的
the warmth of a blanket you cannot replicate.
毯子
Blanket.
毫无疑问
Absolutely.
毯子可以覆盖整个身体
It covers your whole body.
如果需要枕头  只要把毯子卷起来就行了
You know if you need a pillow you just roll it up and you got a pillow.
你可以用毯子把自己卷起来
And you can surround yourself
创造一个舒适温馨的小空间
and make it into a wonderful little cozy space for you
因为枕头可以放在任何地方
because pillows they can go anywhere.
这很疯狂  甚至可能携带疾病
It's pretty crazy and they carry disease.
我觉得自己可能在两边都能找到归属感
I could see myself on either side
我欣赏阿布蒂对细节的专注和他的完美主义
I appreciate Abed's attention to detail and his perfectionism
同时我也喜欢特洛伊的娱乐精神和他的随和天性
and then I like Troy's spirit of fun and his sort of easygoing nature so
所以我两边都有点倾向  能这样说吗
So, a little bit of both. How about that?
我更倾向于舒适自在的东西
I'm more of a like a a snuggie kind of person.
我认为这一集绝对是天才之作  因为这正是本剧的特色
No I thought this is going to be a genius episode because this is what this show does.
这集将传统的情景喜剧格式彻底颠覆
It takes a traditional situation comedy kind of format and just turns it on its head
我觉得这非常棒
and I just think that's great.
我觉得这集非常大胆  再一次打破常规
I thought it was so adventurous and so pushing the envelope yet again
去拍一部关于这场枕毯堡战争的纪录片
to do a documentary about this epic pillow fort blanket fort war.
对我来说  最精彩的部分是看布雷塔拍那些拙劣的照片
The highlight for me was watching Britta taking inept photos
布雷塔这个角色  真是个瑰宝
Britta, that character is just yeah she's a gem man.
甚至昨天看着你们站在那儿  我都觉得很棒
There's something so great even yesterday watching you guys stand there and you're like
裹着毛毯和枕套  互相用枕头打闹
wrapped in blankets and pillowcases hitting each other with pillows and I was like
心想  这就是我们的工作  每周如此
this is our job, this is pretty cool that like every week it is
每周都在做不同的  傻气的  怪异的  不可思议的事情
something different and silly and weird and incredible.
我最喜欢的是上半部分的最后一幕  特洛伊和阿布蒂
I love the moment at the end it's when we see the slow-mo shots of Troy and Abed
在慢镜头中相互凝视  试图抑制他们身后的混乱
looking across the room at each other as they try to restrain the rabble behind them.
唐纳德和丹尼这两位非常有趣的演员
The depth that Donald Glover and Danny Pudi who guys who are so funny
他们完全不需要深入挖掘
they have no need to go that deep
凭借他们的喜剧才能本可以轻松过关
because they're funny enough to subsist purely on comedy chops.
但他们还是为了展现本剧戏剧性的一面而煞费苦心
They bother to play Community for its dramatic points
为了更好地传达剧情
when necessary to tell the story.
别看我
Don't look at me.
我穿着睡衣
I'm wearing my pajamies
因为我的肌肉紧绷
cuz I got hammies that are tight.
让它们放松
Got to stretch them
然后我会说晚安
and then I'll say good night
因为外面很黑  我累了  兄弟
cuz it's dark out yo and I'm tired bro
我一整天都在打你  扔你
I've been up all day hitting you and throw
扔我的枕头
with my pillows.
枕头大战是个啥
What is the pillow war?
傻瓜  你知道我在说啥
Fool. You know what I'm talking about.
毯子是你的武器  你将它裹起
The blanket is your tool and you wrap it around
但它啥都没用  因为它不大惊小怪
but it ain't doing nothing cuz it's not fussing.
我在垒中坐
When I'm in the fort.
行动暂过
We gotta abort.
收工
And ending.